Dearborn, Frederick M. (Frederick Myers), b. 1876, collector. Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy, 1832-1915 (MS Am 1649.24): Guide.
Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy,
- Dunnington, James W. Printed D.s.; Lynchburg, 15 Oct 1863., (233); 1s.(2p.)
- Dunovant, John, 1825-1864. A.L.s. to Nathan George Evans; Sullivans Island, 15 Mar 1861., (234); 1s.(1p.)
- Durel, P. A.L.s. to Col. [] Vincent; Camp Harding, 3 Mar 1865., (235); 1s.(2p.)
- Early, Jubal Anderson, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to Thomas Jordan; [] 18 Jul 1861., (236); 1s.(1p.)
- Echols, John, 1823-1896. A.L.s. to William Smith; Dublin, 17 Sep 1864., (237); 1s.(4p.)
- Echols, John, 1823-1896. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 17 Jul 1864., (238); 1s.(1p.)
- Elliott, Stephen, 1830-1866. A.L.s. to Capt. John M. Otey; [n.p.] 12 Jun 1864., (239); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard.
- Ellis, John Willis, 1820-1861. 2 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Raleigh, 7 Jun 1861., (240); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 10 Jun 1861., (241); 1s.(1p.)
- Elmore, E. C. A.L.s. to Thomas Stanley Bocock; Richmond, 7 Dec 1863., (242); 1s.(2p.)
- Elmore, E. C. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Richmond, 28 oct 1863., (243); 1s.(2p.)
- Elzey, Arnold, 1816-1871. A.L.s. to Henry Alexander Wise; Richmond, 7 Apr 1863., (244); 1s.(3p.)
- Erlanger, Emile. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Paris, 31 Mar 1863., (245); 1s.(2p.)
- Evans, Clement Anselm, 1833-1911. Photograph s.; [n.p., n.d.], (246); 1s.(1p.)
- Evans, Nathan George, 1824-1868. 2 A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard:
  - Leesburg, 15 Sep 1861., (247); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 21 Oct 1861., (248); 1s.(3p.)
- Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert, 1810-1894. A.L.s. to John R. Thompson; Williamsburg, 3 Jan 1866., (249); 1s.(1p.)
- Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert, 1810-1894. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Tullahoma, Tenn., 11 Apr 1863., (250); 1s.(2p.)
- Ewell, Richard Stoddert, 1817-1872. A.L.s. to Col. John B. Sale; Chaffins Farm, 7 Jul 1864., (251); 1s.(2p.)
- Fagan, James Fleming, 1828-1893. 2 A.L.s. to Sterling Price:
  - Prairie Grove, 2 Nov 1864., (252); 1s.(2p.)
  - Washington, Ark., 31 Mar 1865., (253); 1s.(1p.)
- Faulkner, Charles James, 1806-1889. Photograph s.; [n.p.] 27 Nov 1888., (254); 1s.(1p.)
- Featherston, Winfield Scott, 1819-1891. A.L.s. to Edward Porter Alexander; Holly Springs, 27 Nov 1867., (255); 1s.(3p.)
- Ferguson, Samuel Wragg, 1834-1917. A.L.s. to Col. W. H. Allen; Jackson, Tenn., 10 Mar 1862., (256); 1s.(2p.)
- Ferguson, Samuel Wragg, 1834-1917. A.L.s. to Capt. John M. Otey; Jamestown Station, 12 Apr [1865?], (257); 1s.(2p.)
- Ferguson, Samuel Wragg, 1834-1917. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 4 Jan 1864., (258); 1s.(1p.)
- Field, Charles William, 1828-1892. A.L.s. to Henry Lewis Benning; [n.p.] 24 Mar 1865., (259); 1s.(1p.)
- Finley, Jesse Johnson, 1812-1904. A.L.s. to Belmont Perry; Lake City, 10 Apr 1896., (260); 1s.(2p.)
- Flanagin, Harris, 1817-1874. 3 A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Little Rock, 5 Jan 1863., (261); 2s.(7p.)
  - Same, 26 Jun 1863., (262); 1s.(3p.)
  - Washington, Ark., 21 Feb 1865., (263); 1s.(2p.)
- Flanagin, Harris, 1817-1874. MS.L.s. to Edmund Kirby Smith; Little Rock, 15 Jun 1863., (264); 2s.(5p.)
- Flash, Henry Lyden, 1835- A.L.s. to [] Thompson; Galvaston, 15 Feb 1867., (265); 1s.(3p.)
- Floyd, John Buchanan, 1806-1863. 2 MS.L.s. (by adjutant) to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Camp Sewell, 15 Sep 1861., (266); 2s.(5p.)
  - [N.p., n.d.], (267); 3s.(5p.)
- Floyd, John Buchanan, 1806-1863. MS.L.s. to Col. [] Spaulding; Camp Preston, 20 Aug 1861., (268); 1s.(1p.)
- Forney, John Horace, 1829-1902. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Mobile, 17 May 1862., (269); 1s.(2p.)
  With reply be Beauregard.
- Forney, John Horace, 1829-1902. MS.L.s. to Lt. Col. G. G. Gaines; Mobile, 14 Aug 1862., (270); 1s.(2p.)
- Forney, John Horace, 1829-1902. A.L.s. to [] Hunter; [], 18 Feb 1861., (271); 1s.(2p.)
- Forney, John Horace, 1829-1902. A.L.s. to [Belmont Perry]; Jacksonville, Ala., 27 Mar 1896., (272); 1s.(2p.)
  On back of T.L.s. to Forney from Perry.
  - Cotton Exchange clipping
  - "Endorsement" ms. with clippings
  - Typescript on verso of "Endorsement"
- Forney, William Henry, 1823-1894. Photograph s.; [n.p, n.d.], (273); 1s.(1p.)
- Forrest, French, 1796-1866. 2 MS.L.s. to Stephen Russell Mallory:
  - Richmond, 22 Jul 1862., (274); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same], 25 Oct 1862., (275); 1s.(2p.)
- Forrest, Nathan Bedford, 1821-1877. MS.L.s. to Thomas Jordan; Prestonville, 15 Aug 1862., (276); 1s.(2p.)
- Frazer, John Wesley, 1827-1906. A.L.s. to James Barnet Fry; Johnsons Island, 19 Mar 1864., (277); 1s.(1p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- French, S. Bassett. A.L.s. to Basil Brawner; Richmond, 7 Jun 1861., (278); 1s.(2p.)
- French, Samuel Gibbs, 1818-1910. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Wilmington, 29 Mar 1862., (279); 1s.(2p.)
- French, Samuel Gibbs, 1818-1910. A.L.s. to James Birdseye McPherson; Meridian, 30 Nov 1863., (280); 1s.(2p.)
- French, Samuel Gibbs, 1818-1910. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Petersburg, 15 Mar 1863., (281); 1s.(2p.)
- Frenholm, G. A. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Richmond, 25 Feb 1865., (282); 1s.(2p.)
- Frost, Daniel Marsh, 1823-1900. A.L.s. to Thomas Lowndes Snead; [n.p.] 7 Sep 1863., (283); 1s.(2p.)
  With reply by Snead.
- Frost, Daniel Marsh, 1823-1900. MS.D.s.; near Memphis, 21 Apr 1862., (284); 1s.(1p.)
- Fry, Birkett Davenport, 1822-1891. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Augusta, 27 Sep 1864., (285); 1s.(4p.)
- Fry, Birkett Davenport, 1822-1891. A.L.s. to Col. George William Brent; Augusta, 17 Feb 1865., (286); 1s.(1p.)
- Fry, Birkett Davenport, 1822-1891. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Augusta, 8 Jan 1865., (287); 1s.(2p.)
- Fry, Birkett Davenport, 1822-1891. A.L.s. to A. I. Ford; Augusta, 23 Feb 1865., (288); 1s.(2p.)
- Gamble, Hamilton Rowan, 1798-1864. Printed D.s.; St. Louis, 26 Sep 1862., (289); 1s.(1p.)
- Gano, Richard Montgomery, 1830-1913. A.L.s. to Belmont Perry; Dallas, 6 Feb 1880., (290); 1s.(1p.)
- Gantt, Edward W. A.L.s. to E. R. Perkins; Jackson, 4 Mar 1865., (291); 1s.(2p.)
- Gantt, Edward W. A.L.s. to Leonidas Polk; Fort Thompson, Mo., 1 Jan 1862., (292); 1s.(1p.)
- Gardner, Franklin, 1823-1873. 2 MS.L. (telegrams) to Samuel Cooper:
  - Mobile, 19 Aug 1864., (293); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 23 Aug 1864., (294); 1s.(1p.)
- Gardner, Franklin, 1823-1873. 2 A.L.s. to Maj. R. W. Memminger:
  - Port Hudson, La., 24 Apr 1863., (295); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 25 Apr 1863., (296); 1s.(2p.)
- Gardner, Franklin, 1823-1873. MS.L.s. to Maj. Daniel E. Huger; Munfordsville, Ky., 19 Sep 1862., (297); 1s.(2p.)
- Gardner, William Montgomery, 1824-1901. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 18 Sep 1864., (298); 1s.(2p.)
- Garnett, Richard Brooke, 1817-1863. A.L.s. to Col. [] Mumford; Richmond, 24 Apr 1861., (299); 1s.(2p.)
- Garnett, Richard Brooke, 1817-1863. A.L.s. to [] Early; [n.p., ca. 1840-1841?], (300); 1s.(2p.)
- Garrett, Thomas M. A.L.s. to Maj. A. G. Pendleton; [n.p.] 2 Apr 1863., (301); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Robert Hall Chilton.
- Gartrell, Lucius Jeremiah, 1821-1891. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Atlanta, 1 Aug 1863., (302); 1s.(4p.)
- Gary, Martin Witherspoon, 1831-1881. A.L.s. to Lt. Col. G. M. Lorrel; Fussells Farm, 2 Aug 1864., (303); 1s.(1p.)
- Gates, Elija. MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (304); 3s.(12p.)
- Gatlin, Richard Caswell, 1809-1896. A.L.s. to Col. I. G. Martin; Wilmington, 8 Aug 1861., (305); 1s.(2p.)
- Gholson, Samuel Jameson, 1808-1883. A.L.s. to Daniel Ruggles; [n.p.] 6 May 1863., (306); 1s.(1p.)
- Gibbs, George, 1815-1873. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Macon, 4 Aug 1864., (307); 1s.(1p.)
- Gibson, Randall Lee, 1832-1892. A.L.s. to [William Preston Johnston]; near Shelbyville, 26 Nov 1862., (308); 2s.(6p.)
  Endorsed by Johnston.
- Gilmer, Jeremy Francis, 1818-1883. A.L.s. to Col. William Montague Browne; Richmond, 23 Mar 1863., (309); 1s.(1p.)
- Gilmer, Jeremy Francis, 1818-1883. MS.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Richmond, 25 Sep 1862., (310); 1s.(4p.)
- Gilmor, Harry, 1828-1883. A.L.s. to G. H. Stettson; Baltimore, 6 Jul 1882., (311); 1s.(1p.)
- Gist, States Rights, 1831-1864. A.L.s. to Col. Robert Barnwell Rhett; Columbia, 29 Dec 1861., (312); 1s.(2p.)
- Gist, States Rights, 1831-1864. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Charleston, 20 Jun 1861., (313); 1s.(3p.)
- Gladden, Adley Hogan, 1810-1862. A.L.s. to Daniel Ruggles; Bethel, Tenn., 11 Mar 1862., (314); 1s.(1p.)
- Godwin, Archibald Campbell, 1831-1864. A.L.s. to [] Semple; near Orange C. H., 2 Aug 1863., (315); 1s.(2p.)
- Gordon, John Brown, 1832-1904. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Columbus, Ga., 7 Aug 1865., (316); 1s.(2p.)
- Gordon, John Brown, 1832-1904. A.L.s. to Frank []; Richmond, 28 Jun 1862., (317); 1s.(2p.)
- Gordon, John Brown, 1832-1904. MS.D.s.; near Leesburg, 15 Jul 1864., (318); 1s.(2p.)
- Gordon, William F. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 28 Jan 1861., (319); 1s.(1p.)
- Gorgas, Josiah, 1841-1883. MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 6 Mar 1863., (320); 1s.(2p.)
- Gorgas, Josiah, 1841-1883. MS.L.s. to Col. Joseph Christmas Ives; Richmond, 11 Jul 1862., (321); 1s.(2p.)
- Gorgas, Josiah, 1841-1883. A.L.s. to Col. Edward Manigault; Montgomery, 7 May 1861., (322); 1s.(2p.)
- Gracie, Archibald, 1832-1864. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 25 Sep 1864., (323); 1s.(2p.)
- Grayson, John Breckinridge, 1806-1861. A.L.s. to [] Crawford; Detroit, 7 Aug 1832., (324); 1s.(1p.)
- Green, Allen J. A.L.s. to States Rights Gist; Charleston Harbor, 3 Jan 1861., (325); 1s.(2p.)
- Green, Martin Edwin, 1815-1863. A.L.s. to Maj. []; [], 19 Mar 1863., (326); 1s.(4p.)
- Green, Thomas, 1814-1864. A.L.s. to W. S. Ploham; Vermillionville, 13 Dec 1863., (327); 1s.(2p.)
- Greer, Elkhanah Brackin, 1825-1877. A.L.s. to Edmund Kirby Smith; Marshall, 23 Nov 1864., (328); 1s.(2p.)
- Gregg, John, 1828-1864. A.D.s.; Marshall, 8 Oct 1861., (329); 1s.(1p.)
- Gregg, Maxcy, 1814-1862. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Centreville, 9 Jul 1861., (330); 1s.(1p.)
- Gregg, Maxcy, 1814-1862. A.L.s. to States Rights Gist; Sullivans Island, 8 Jan. 1861., (331); 1s.(2p.)
- Gregory, John M. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Charles City, 26 Dec 1862., (332); 1s.(2p.)
- Griffith, George R. A.L.s. to Edwin Cary Walthall, Atlanta, 4 Aug 1863., (333); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Walthall.
- Griffith, Richard, 18l4-1862. A.L.s. to [Mrs. Richard Griffith]; Richmond, 29 Nov 1861., (334); 1s.(2p.)
- Grimes, Bryan, 1828-1880. A.L.s. to Robert Hall Chilton; camp near Orange, Va., 22 Aug 1863., (335); 1s.(2p.)
- Grimes, Bryan, 1828-1880. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] Apr 1865., (336); 1s.(2p.)
- Hagan, James. MS.L. (unsigned copy) to Capt. B. A. Jewett; Aiken, 10 Feb 1865., (337); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Joseph Wheeler.
- Hagood, Johnson, 1829-1898. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (338); 1s.(1p.)
- Hahn, Michael, 1830-1886. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (339); 1s.(1p.)
- Hallonquist, James H. MS.D.s.; Fort Moultrie, 17 Jan 1861., (340); 1s.(2p.)
- Hamilton, Andrew Jackson, 1815-1876. Printed D.s.; Austin, 22 Dec 1865., (341); 1s.(2p.)
- Hammond, James Henry, 1807-1864. A.L.s. to Col. H. M. Walter; Chattanooga, 10 Aug 1863., (342); 1s.(2p.)
- Hampton, Wade, 1818-1902. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Columbia, 6 Aug 1863., (343); 1s.(4p.)
  Endorsed by Davis.
- Hampton, Wade, 1818-1902. A.L.s. to William Porcher Miles; [n.p.] 31 Dec 1864., (344); 1s.(4p.)
- Hanson, J. W. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Richmond, 25 Aug 1862., (345); 1s.(3p.)
- Hanson, J. W. A.L.s. to Col. A. C. Myers; Richmond, 3 Jul 1862., (346); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by George Wythe Randolph.
- Hardee, D. C. A.L.s. to J. G. Kilbourne; [n.p.] 15 Aug 1862., (347); 1s.(2p.)
- Hardee, D. C. A.L.s. to [Daniel] Ruggles; near Baton Rouge, 15 Aug 1862., (348); 1s.(2p.)
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - [N.p.] 27 Sep 1864., (349); 1s.(3p.)
  - Charleston, 12 Oct 1864., (350); 1s.(4p.)
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. A.L.s. to Joseph [Christmas] Ives; Dalton, 23 Dec 1863., (351); 1s.(2p.)
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. 2 MS.L.s. to William Preston Johnston:
  - Tullahoma, Tenn, 13 Jan 1863., (352); 1s.(4p.)
  - Charleston, 23 Jan 1865., (353); 1s.(3p.)
    The latter endorsed by Jefferson Davis.
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. A.L.s. to Gideon Johnson Pillow; Greenville, Mo., 27 Aug 1861., (354); 1s.(2p.)
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. A.L.s. to Earl Van Dorn; [Corinth?] 28 May 1862., (355); 1s.(2p.)
- Hardee, William Joseph, 1815-1873. A.L.s. to Sydney []; Corinth, 15 Apr 1862., (356); 1s.(1p.)
- Hardin, John B. A.L.s. to Capt. [] Roddy; [n.p.] 24 Feb 1862., (357); 1s.(2p.)
- Harllee, William W. A.L.s. to James Chesnut; Laurel Hill, 25 Feb 1862., (358); 1s.(4p.)
- Harris, E. H. A.L.s. to Lt. J. H. Ewell; Montgomery, 7 Jan 1863., (359); 1s.(1p.)
- Harris, George C. A.L.s. to George Birdseye McPherson; Jackson, 22 Jan [1864?], (360); 1s.(1p.)
- Harris, Isham Green, 1818-1897. A.L.s. to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Memphis, 13 Apr 1876., (361); 1s.(4p.); Description of the death of Albert Sidney Johnston.
- Harris, Isham Green, 1818-1897. 3 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Nashville, 20 Apr 1861., (362); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 2 Jul 1861., (363); 1s.(4p.)
  - Meridian, 16 Jan 1864., (364); 1s.(4p.)
- Harris, Nathaniel Harrison, 1834-1900. A.L.s. to Richard Heron Anderson; [n.p.] 2 Dec 1864., (365); 1s.(1p.)
- Hawes, Richard. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 11 Jan 1865., (366); 2s.(8p.)
  This is the same person as items (377-378). Previously incorrectly identified.
- Harrison, Burton N. A.L.s. to Robert Grame; Richmond, 31 Jul 1862., (367); 1s.(2p.)
- Harrison, George T. MS.L.s. to Henry Constantine Wayne; Savannah, 10 Jan 1862., (368); 1s.(2p.)
- Harrison, James Edward, 1815-1875. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; near Waco, 9 Dec 1911., (369); 1s.(2p.)
- Harrison, Richard. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Aberdeen, 30 Jul 1863., (370); 1s.(2p.)
- Harrison, Thomas, 1823-1875. A.L.s. to Maj. W. E. Wailes; [n.p.] 18 Oct 1864., (371); 1s.(2p.)
- Harrison, Thomas, 1823-1875. A.L.s. (fragment: endorsement); [n.p.] 30 Jan 1865., (372); 1s.(2p.)
- Harte, R. N.? A.L.s. to Marsena Rudolph Patrick; [n.p.] 27 May 1865., (373); 1s.(1p.)
- Haskell, Charles T., Jr. MS.D.s.; Sullivans Island, 29 May 1861., (374); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Barnard Elliott Bee.
- Hatton, Robert Hopkins, 1826-1862. A.L.s.to Capt. []; Washington, 5 Mar 1860., (375); 1s.(3p.)
- Hawes, James Morrison, 1824-1889. Endorsement s.; [n.p.] 20 Sep 1863., (376); 1s.(1p.)
- Hawes, Richard. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Richmond, 10 Jan 1863., (377); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 29 Nov 1864., (378); 1s.(4p.)
- Hayes, Harry Thompson, 1820-1876. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; North Carolina, 12 May 1875., (379); 1s.(1p.)
- Hayes, Harry Thompson, 1820-1876. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 20 Dec 1862., (380); 1s.(4p.)
- Hébert, Louis, 1820-1901. A.L.s. to Capt. James M. Loughborough; Camp Sloan, 17 Nov 1862., (381); 1s.(2p.)
- Hébert, Louis, 1820-1901. A.L.s. to [Sterling] Price; Camp Benjamin, Ark., 17 Feb 1862., (382); 1s.(1p.)
- Hébert, Louis, 1820-1901. MS.L.s. to Maj. R. Strange; Wilmington, Feb 1865., (383); 1s.(3p.)
  Includes copy of telegram from William Henry Chase Whiting.
- Hébert, Paul Octave, 1818-1880. Printed D.s.; Baton Rouge, 10 Mar 1854., (384); 1s.(2p.)
- Henderson, R. H. A.L.s. to []; Drewry's Bluff, 18 Feb 1863., (385); 1s.(2p.)
- Heth, Henry, 1825-1899. Photograph s.; [n.p., n.d.], (386); 1s.(1p.)
- Hickey, James. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Castle Thunder, 25 Mar 1863., (387); 1s.(2p.)
- Higgins, Edward, 1821-1875. A.L.s. to Lt. J. G. Devereux; [n.p.] 29 Nov 1861., (388); 1s.(4p.)
- Hill, Ambrose Powell, 1825-1865. A.L.s. to [Lawrence O'Bryan] Branch; [n.p.] 6 Jun 1862., (389); 1s.(2p.)
  With reply by Branch.
- Hill, Ambrose Powell, 1825-1865. A.L.s. to Robert Edward Lee; [n.p.] 18 Sep 1863., (390); 1s.(3p.)
- Hill, Benjamin Jefferson, 1825-1880. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Opelika, 1 Feb 1865., (391); 1s.(2p.)
- Hill, Benjamin Jefferson, 1825-1880. MS.L. (telegram) to []; Oxford, 8 Feb [1864], (392); 2s.(3p.)
  First two pages missing.
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; near Augusta, 1 Feb 1865., (393); 1s.(2p.)
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Hill, Ambrose Powell. Petersburg, 6 Jun 1863., (394); 1s.(2p.)
    Formerly thought to be by Daniel Hill. Ambrose Hill Lt. Gen. III Corps Army of Northern Virginia, CSA.
  - Richmond, 16 Nov 1863., (395); 1s.(4p.)
    The first endorsed by Davis.
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. A.L.s. to Thomas Jordan; Leesburg, 10 Dec 1861., (396); 1s.(3p.)
  Endorsed by Joseph Eggleston Johnston.
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. A.L.s. to Robert Edward Lee; [n.p.] 9 Aug 1863., (397); 1s.(2p.)
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. A.L.s. to Gustavus Woodson Smith; near Hanover Junction, 25 Aug 1862., (398); 1s.(2p.)
- Hill, Daniel Harvey, 1821-1889. A.L.s. to Zebulon Baird Vance; Kinston, N. C., 25 May 1863., (399); 1s.(2p.)
- Hilliard, Henry Washington, 1808-1892. A.L.s. to [] Capers; Montgomery, 19 Mar [1861], (400); 1s.(2p.)
- Hindman, Thomas Carmichael, 1828-1868. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Helena, Ark., 18 Apr 1861., (401); 1s.(2p.)
  With reply by Beauregard.
- Hindman, Thomas Carmichael, 1828-1868. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Dalton, 16 Jan 1864., (402); 1s.(3p.)
- Hindman, Thomas Carmichael, 1828-1868. MS.L. (telegram) to [Leonidas] Polk; Murfreesboro, 20 Feb 1862., (403); 1s.(2p.)
  In hand of Pierre Gustave Toutant Beauregard.
- Hindman, Thomas Carmichael, 1828-1868. A.L.s. to Dr. [] Stout; Macon, 24 Jul 1864., (404); 1s.(2p.)
- Hines, P. E. A.L.s. to Samuel Preston Moore; Raleigh, 21 Mar 1865., (405); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Moore.
- Hobson, Amson W. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Tupelo, 24 Aug 1862., (406); 1s.(2p.)
- Hodge, George Baird, 1829-1892. 2 A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - [N.p.] 22 Mar 1865., (407); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p., n.d.], (408); 2s.(5p.)
- Hogan, J. B. A.L.s. to Col. G. M. Sorrel; [n.p.] 31 Mar 1864., (409); 1s.(2p.)
- Hogg, Joseph Lewis, 1806-1862. A.L.s. to Wallace McDugald; Duvalls Bluff 12 Apr 1862., (410); 1s.(1p.)
- Hogg, Joseph Lewis, 1806-1862. MS.D.s.; near Memphis, 23 Apr 1862., (411); 1s.(2p.)
- Hoke, Robert Frederick, 1837-1912. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Drewry's Bluff, 15 Jan 1864., (412); 1s.(2p.)
- Hoke, Robert Frederick, 1837-1912. MS.L. (unsigned copy) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Plymouth, N. C., 22 Apr 1864., (413); 1s.(3p.)
- Hoke, Robert Frederick, 1837-1912. A.L.s. to [Braxton] Bragg; Plymouth, 20 Apr 1864., (414); 1s.(1p.)
- Hoke, William J. A.L.s. to Col. John M. Otey; Charlotte, 28 Feb 1865., (415); 1s.(2p.)
- Holmes, Theophilus Hunter, 1804-1880. A.L.s. to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Fredericksburg, 13 Jun 1861., (416); 1s.(2p.)
- Holmes, Theophilus Hunter, 1804-1880. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Camden, 24 Dec 1863., (417); 1s.(4p.)
- Holmes, Theophilus Hunter, 1804-1880. MS.L. (telegram) to [Joseph Eggleston] Johnston; Brooks Station, 28 Oct [1861], (418); 1s.(1p.)
  With reply by Johnston.
- Holtzclaw, James Thadeus, 1833-1893. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Meridian, 6 May 1865., (419); 1s.(1p.)
- Hood, John Bell, 1831-1879. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 21 Mar 1865., (420); 1s.(3p.)
- Houston, Samuel, 1793-1863. Printed D.s.; Austin, 30 Dec 1859., (421); 1s.(1p.)
- Huger, Benjamin, 1805-1877. A.L.s. to Warren Winslow; Norfolk, 19 Jul 1861., (422); 1s.(2p.)
- Huger, Benjamin, 1805-1877. A.L.s. to []; [n.p., n.d.], (423); 1s.(1p.)
- Huger, John M. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Mobile, 30 Jul 1862., (424); 1s.(4p.)
- Humes, W. Y. C. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (425); 1s.(1p.)
- Humphries, Benjamin Grubbs, 1808-1882. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; [n.p., n.d.], (426); 1s.(1p.)
- Hunton, Eppa, 1822-1908. A.L.s. to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; near Leesburg, 30 Oct 1861., (427); 1s.(2p.)
- Hunton, Eppa, 1822-1908. A.L.s. to Philip St. George Cocke; Leesburg, 24 Jun 1861., (428); 1s.(3p.)
  With copy of reply by Cocke.
- Imboden, John Daniel, 1823-1895. A.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Hardy Co., Va., 26 Sep 1862., (429); 1s.(2p.)
- Imboden, John Daniel, 1823-1895. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Stounton, 18 Jul 1863., (430); 1s.(2p.)
- Ingraham, Duncan Nathaniel, 1802-1891. A.L.s. to H. Y. Purviance; Philadelphia, 6 Jan 1851., (431); 1s.(2p.)
- Iverson, Alfred, 1829-1911. A.L.s. to Lt. [] Hudson; [n.p.] 24 Dec 1864., (432); 1s.(2p.)
- Iverson, Alfred, 1829-1911. MS.D.s.; Greensboro, 5 Apr 1865., (433); 1s.(1p.)
- Ives, Joseph Christmas, 1828-1868. A.L.s. to Mansfield Lovell; Richmond, 29 May 1862., (434); 1s.(1p.)
- Ives, Joseph Christmas, 1828-1868. A.L.s. to []; Washington, 1 Aug 1859., (435); 1s.(1p.)
- Jackson, Alfred Eugene, 1807-1889. A.L.s. to Maj. J. Stoddard Johnson; Glade Springs, Va., 6 Dec 1864., (436); 1s.(2p.)
- Jackson, Claiborne Fox, 1806-1862. A.L.s. to John Bullock Clark [Sr.]; New Orleans, 30 Dec 1861., (437); 1s.(2p.)
- Jackson, Claiborne Fox, 1806-1862. 3 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Jefferson City, 2 Jun 1861., (438); 1s.(1p.)
  - New Orleans, 30 Dec 1861., (439); 1s.(2p.)
  - Marshall, Tex., 28 Jul 1862., (440); 1s.(2p.)
- Jackson, Claiborne Fox, 1806-1862. A.L.s. to []; Memphis, 10 Aug 1861., (441); 1s.(4p.)
- Jackson, John King, 1828-1899. A.L.s. to Capt. []; Pensacola, 23 Jun 1861., (442); 1s.(3p.)
- Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1824-1863. A.L.s. to Alexander Robinson Boteler; Winchester, 25 Feb 1862., (443); 1s.(2p.)
- Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1824-1863. A.L.s. to Richard Stoddard Ewell; [n.p., 19 Jul 1862?], (444); 1s.(1p.)
- Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1824-1863. 3 A.L.s. to William Lowther Jackson:
  - Sharpsburg, 16 Sep 1862., (445); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.] 21 Jan 1863., (446); 2s.(3p.)
  - Caroline Co., La., 13 Feb 1863., (447); 1s.(4p.)
- Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1824-1863. Printed D.s.; Jefferson County, Va., 21 May 1861., (448); 1s.(1p.)
- Jackson, W. H. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; [n.p.] 22 Aug 1864., (449); 1s.(3p.)
- Jackson, William Hicks, 1835-1903. 2 MS.L.s. to James Birdseye McPherson:
  - Livingston, 21 Oct 1863., (450); 1s.(2p.)
  - Canton, Miss., 8 Mar 1864., (451); 1s.(2p.)
- Jackson, William Lowther, 1825-1890. A.L.s. to John Letcher; Richmond, 14 May 1861., (452); 1s.(2p.)
- Jenkins, Albert Gallatin, 1830-1864. A.L.s. to []; Richmond, 4 Apr 1862., (453); 1s.(2p.)
- Jenkins, Micah, 1835-1864. A.L.s. to Arnold Elzey; Petersburg, 18 Aug 1863., (454); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Adam Rankin, 1834-1922. MS.L.s. to Allen E. Wright; [Burnet?] 1915., (455); 1s.(1p.)
- Johnson, Bradley Tyler, 1829-1903. A.L.s. to Arnold Elzey; [n.p.] 28 Mar 1864., (456); 1s.(4p.)
- Johnson, Bradley Tyler, 1829-1903. A.L.s. to Col. [John M.] Otey; Salisbury, 1 Mar 1865., (457); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Bushrod Rust, 1817-1880. 2 A.L.s. to Capt. John M. Otey:
  - [N.p.] 8 Jun 1864., (458); 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 13 Jun 1864., (459); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Bushrod Rust, 1817-1880. A.L.s. to Marcus Joseph Wright; Tullahoma, 15 Apr 1863., (460); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Edward, 1816-1873. A.L.s. to Lt. G. Andrews; Camp Alaghary, 6 Aug 1861., (461); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Edward, 1816-1873. A.L.s. to Maj. W. H. Taylor; [n.p.] 27 May 1863., (462); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Edward, 1816-1873. A.L.s. to []; Camp Barton, 30 Sep 1861., (463); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, George W. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Bowling Green, 21 Nov 1861., (464); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1803-1862. A.L.s. to [Samuel] Cooper; Washington, 18 May 1860., (465); 1s.(1p.)
- Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1803-1862. MS.L. (telegram) to Isham Green Harris; Bowling Green, 24 Jan 1862., (466); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1803-1862. A.L.s. to []; Camp Floyd, Utah, 10 May 1859., (467); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1803-1862. A.L.s. to [] San Francisco, 14 Apr 1861., (468); 1s.(4p.)